chipverify.com 2018-09-28

# Privacy Policy | Info

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

## What personal information do we collect ?

### Account and Profile Information

There are primarily two ways to create an account or profile in ChipVerify which are discussed below: 

  1. _Using LinkedIn or Facebook_ : When you try to register with ChipVerify using a LinkedIn or Facebook account, we only take the full name, photo, current position, your summary and the link to your public profile in the respective social media site. We obtain these information directly from LinkedIn and Facebook and is shared on your profile page in ChipVerify. You have the control to set privacy for these information if you wish not to share with other members of ChipVerify. We ask you to login to LinkedIn and Facebook directly and hence your passwords or usernames are not stored in our database.
  2. _Using ChipVerify registration page_ : Basic information that you provide will be used to build your profile in ChipVerify and you have control to change this data at a future date if you would like to.

### Social Media Login

If you elect to sign up through or connect a Linked Network, we receive certain profile and account information about you from the Linked Network. These Linked Networks may also appear in your profile, so that people can find you on these Linked Networks. The specific information provided to us by Linked Networks is determined by these third parties and may vary by network. In all cases, the permissions page for the Linked Network will describe the information being shared. You should consult their respective privacy policies for information about their practices. You may elect to use information from the Linked Network to populate your profile on the ChipVerify Platform and help you find and follow your contacts on the ChipVerify Platform. For information on your choices, including how to disconnect a Linked Network from your ChipVerify profile, please visit their site to obtain information.

Your name and photo that you choose to add to your public-facing profile will be available for viewing to users of this website. However, only registered users have access to the links to your social media profiles, current employment and other details available on the profile page in ChipVerify. Once you create a profile, other users will be able to see in your profile certain information about your activity on the ChipVerify platform, such as the questions and answers you post, the status you share, the events you create and the blogs you publish.

### Content

We collect and store the information and content that you post on ChipVerify, including your question and answers in the forum, profile photo and status and any other information that you provide us. This may be indexed by search engines and republished elsewhere on the Internet.

When you communicate with us via email, we may maintain a record of your communication.

### Engagement

We collect browsing information - such as IP address and location, date and time stamp, user agent, social media cookies (if applicable), URL, unique advertising or content identifiers (if applicable) and time zone, and other information about user activities on the ChipVerify Platform.

## How we use your information

We do not sell your personal data - such as your name and contact informaiton - to third parties to use for their own marketing purposes. We collect the information for the following purposes:

  * To provide our service, communicate with you about your use of the platform, respond to your inquiries, provide troubleshooting and for other customer service purposes.
  * To display interest-based advertising to you in the ChipVerify Platform, to improve our advertising and measurement systems so we can show you relevant ads, and to measure the effectiveness and reach of ads and services.
  * To gather metrics to better understand how users access and use the website; to evaluate and improve the platform, including the Ad Services and personalization, and to develop new tools and utilities for better experience on our website.

## How we share your information

We _may_ share your information with third party service providers who use this information to perform services for us, such as payment processors, hosting providers, and support providers.

We may disclose information where we believe it necessary to respond to claims asserted against us or, comply with legal process (e.g., subpoenas or warrants), enforce or administer our agreements and terms, for fraud prevention, risk assessment, investigation, and protect the rights, property or safety of ChipVerify, its users, or others. 

Your Content, including your name, profile picture, profile information, and certain associated activity information is available to other users of the ChipVerify Platform and may be viewed publicly. Public viewing includes availability to non-registered visitors and can occur when users share Your Content across other sites or services. In addition, Your Content may be indexed by search engines. See the section below about Your Choices for information about how you may change how certain information is shared or viewed by others.

We may share with users of our advertisers or publishers aggregate statistics, metrics and other reports about the performance of their ads or content in the ChipVerify Platform such as the number of unique user views, demographics about the users who saw their ads or content, conversion rates, and date and time information. We do not share IP addresses or personal information. We may also allow our advertisers or publishers to use Pixels on the ChipVerify Platform in order to collect information about the performance of their ads or content.

We and our third party providers use cookies, clear GIFs/pixel tags, JavaScript, local storage, log files, and other mechanisms to automatically collect and record information about your usage and browsing activities on the ChipVerify Platform.

  * _Cookies_ : These are small files with a unique identifier that are transferred to your browser through our websites. They allow us to remember users who are logged in, to understand how users navigate through and use the ChipVerify Platform, and to display personalized content and targeted ads (including on third party sites and applications).
  * We may use internal and third party analytics tools, including Google Analytics. The third party analytics companies we work with may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online products and services. Their collection and use of information is subject to their own privacy policies.

## How do we protect visitor information?

The security of your information is important to us. ChipVerify has implemented safeguards to protect the information we collect. However, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe, such as choosing a strong password and keeping it private, as well as logging out of your user account, and closing your web browser when finished using the ChipVerify Platform on a shared or unsecured device.

### We do not use an SSL certificate

We do not need an SSL because we do not collect any information other than email address and name, or information provided to us by LinkedIn and Facebook.

## Do we use cookies?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to keep track of advertisements.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It won't affect the users experience that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place orders.

## Third Party Disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety.   
However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Google

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by [ Google's Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en). They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.  
We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We have implemented the following: 

  * Remarketing with Google AdSense We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.
  * Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. - See more at [CALOPPA](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf)

###### According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it in our footer.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found on the page specified above.
  * Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes: • On our Privacy Policy Page Users are able to change their personal information: • By logging in to their account

## How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?

It's also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act) When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online. We do not specifically market to children under 13.

## Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information. In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur: We will notify the users via email : 

  * Within 7 business days We will notify the users via in site notification
  * Within 1 business day We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

## CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to: 

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:
  * NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters
  * Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at [contact@chipverify.com](mailto:contact@chipverify.com) and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence. Contacting Us If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

[Click here to contact us ! 

](mailto:contact@chipverify.com)
